hi my name is Joe Brewer and I'm a
change strategist today I want to share
with you a little bit about a book that
I found really helpful for understanding
the future of scientific research and
open collaboration and that's this book
reinventing discovery the new era of
network science by Michael Nielsen now
this book goes into the rapidly changing
landscape of scientific research with
the advent of new digital communication
tools and the information architectures
that enable massive scale collaboration
that was not frankly possible even just
a few years ago so you're probably
familiar with examples like Wikipedia or
massive numbers of people solve the
problem of accumulating and vetting
knowledge for an encyclopedia but you
may not be familiar with the very
rapidly growing movement of citizen
science or the areas of what are called
big science which are places where math
where thousands of researchers come
together and share huge datasets and
collaborate on big projects so this book
reinventing discovery explores the
question how will open collaboration be
used to solve the most difficult
problems confronting humanity so two
examples that I'll share that I think
give a sense of what this book helps us
all understand better so one example is
the example of Galaxy Zoo Galaxy Zoo is
a website set up by an astrophysicist at
Oxford who realized that their massive
database filled with galaxies some 30
billion galaxies that they had in the
database could not possibly be
categorized by a small number of
researchers so they created a website
where people could join and they could
come and categorize themselves and
unbeknownst to them this was extremely
popular and so the day that they
launched the website it would actually
crashed the servers at the University of
Michigan if I remember correctly because
there were 80 thousand two hundred
thousand new people each hour wanting to
contribute to categorizing galaxies so
what they found was that there was a
huge hunger for people to participate in
research projects and that they were
able to get huge amounts of
collaboration by making it possible for
people to do so so that's the first
thing
the second example is the Human Genome
Project which is of course the attempt
to sequence the entire sequence of DNA
for the human species and that was a
project that involved a combination of
research among several universities and
corporations you know pharmaceutical
biotech companies and that had to invent
new technologies share knowledge create
massive datasets and then move that data
around or as they would say in the world
of big data they had to federate the
data meaning putting it into one place
and making an open access so that more
people could use the data for their
purposes and their own research projects
so this kind of massive scale
collaboration whether it's in society at
large for open-source citizen science
projects or for academic and corporate
research as with biotechnology and
pharmaceuticals development with the
Human Genome Project these kinds of
collaboration processes can teach us a
great deal about how to bring large
numbers of people together and solve
problems that without that collaboration
would have been impossible to solve so
this book by Michael Nielsen reinventing
discovery is an excellent resource to
give you an understanding of how to
start to apply open collaboration and
open innovation principles to problem
solving and you can use this for
societal problems like ridding the world
of poverty or changing the global
financial system or you can use it for
solving technical problems like how to
clean up an oil spill in the Gulf of
Mexico or how to stop a virus from
spreading across the population of
people with all of the connections we
have with our travel patterns and our
human connectivity so these massive
problems that require new ways of
approaching them and large amounts of
collaboration oh that's not possible to
do and if you want to understand how
it's done and how to do it yourself get
this book thank you and enjoy